// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Which of the following best describes Rock?",
    answer: "C. Most rocks are a mixture of minerals",
    options: [
      "A. It is made of one mineral",
      "B. It is not made of mineral",
      "C. Most rocks are a mixture of minerals",
      "D. All of the Above",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Which of the following is NOT a kind of rock?",
    answer: "A. Magma",
    options: [
      "A. Magma",
      "B. Igneous",
      "C. Sedimentary",
      "D. Metamorphic",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Metamorphic rock changes from their original form by ________________.",
    answer: "C. heat and pressure",
    options: [
      "A. pieces of other existing rock",
      "B. cools and solidifies",
      "C. heat and pressure",
      "D. melting of rock",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "A kind of rock forms where there are compilations of sediments over time______.",
    answer: "B. sedimentary",
    options: [
      "A. igneous",
      "B. sedimentary",
      "C. metamorphic",
      "D. granite",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "All of the following are examples of igneous rock, EXCEPT",
    answer: "C. Limestone",
    options: [
      "A. Granite",
      "B. Obsidian",
      "C. Limestone",
      "D. Pumice",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which type of rock do fossils belong?",
    answer: "A. Sedimentary",
    options: [
      "A. Sedimentary",
      "B. Igneous",
      "C. Metamorphic",
      "D. all of these",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "The solid mixture of a rock is called __________________.",
    answer: "D. sediments",
    options: [
      "A. magma",
      "B. minerals",
      "C. lava",
      "D. sediments",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which are examples of non-foliated rocks?",
    answer: "A. marble and quartzite",
    options: [
      "A. marble and quartzite",
      "B. gneiss and schist",
      "C. slate and phyllite",
      "D. all of these",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which of the following is an example of foliated metamorphic rock?",
    answer: "D. slate",
    options: [
      "A. slate",
      "B. limestone",
      "C. marble",
      "D. coal",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which example of igneous rock is formed from rapidly cooling lava?",
    answer: "C. obsidian",
    options: [
      "A. granite",
      "B. pumice",
      "C. obsidian",
      "D. basalt",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "Which of the following processes occur in the rock cycle?",
    answer: "D. all of these",
    options: [
      "A. heat and pressure",
      "B. weathering and erosion",
      "C. cooling and solidification",
      "D. all of these",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Rocks are mixtures of the following, EXCEPT _______",
    answer: "B. organic matter",
    options: [
      "A. Minerals",
      "B. organic matter",
      "C. volcanic glass",
      "D. none of these",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "It is an example of foliated metamorphic rock ________________",
    answer: "D. slate",
    options: [
      "A. coal",
      "B. limestone",
      "C. marble",
      "D. slate",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "Regional metamorphism is caused by ________________________",
    answer: "D. all of these",
    options: [
      "A. heat",
      "B. pressure",
      "C. metamorphism",
      "D. all of these",
    ],
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Students found a metamorphic rock in the campsite. Its presence is evidence that the rock found is from ______________.",
    answer: "A. sediment deposition",
    options: [
      "A. sediment deposition",
      "B. wind-borne sand",
      "C. dinosaur activity",
      "D. high pressure",
    ],
  },
];
